It's a big day for us. We are unveiling
Tessle. We're launching Tessle's
products. And it's it's exciting. We've
been building this for quite a while.
And if you're using agents to develop,
then you've probably seen that agents
are powerful, but they're also
unreliable. So you would ask them for
something, then go off and they rush to
start coding. The first solution that
comes to mind and often times that would
be the wrong thing. For some people,
they just can't get into agentic
development because of this blocker. And
so we think we can address many of these
problems through specs and specdriven
development. That's what both of our
products are trying to solve. What are
the two product that we're releasing?
The first one is the Tesla framework and
that is really a specdriven development
framework. The second product is the
Tesla spec registry. In practice, even
the same person in the same company for
certain tasks. Sometimes you want to
create the spec, review the spec, ensure
that what you mean to build, that your
intent is well captured, that the test
cases represent what you want, and
you're willing to invest that time
because you have enough opinions and
it's important enough or maybe unique
enough. It's rules of some new game and
the Tesla framework supports that, and
it's very easy and natural to do it. And
then once you have defined those, you
send the agent off to build and you have
those guardrails so the agent can work
more autonomously until it gets it
right.
Before
[Music]
we jump into this episode, I wanted to
let you know that this podcast is for
developers building with AI at the core.
So whether that's exploring the latest
tools, the workflows, or the best
practices, this podcast's for you. Now,
we've had amazing guests like Olivier
Pomel, the CEO of Data Dog, Matty
Stanisowski, the co-founder of 11 Labs,
Victor Ripelli, the CEO and co-founder
at Synthesia, and of course, Tessle's
very own Patrick Dubois. And they're all
sharing lessons right from the frontier
of our industry. A really quick ask, 90%
of people who are listening to this
haven't yet subscribed. So, if this
content has helped you build smarter,
hit that subscribe button and maybe a
like. It really does help us keep
bringing the folks who are actually
pushing this space forward and helping
build that AI native future. All right,
back to the episode. Hello and welcome
to another episode of the AI native dev.
And this is a pretty special
episodedeed. Joining me as regular host
is regular host GO. Guy,
>> thanks for coming on to the show. Sim,
>> it's my pleasure. So, uh, who's
interviewing? I'll interview you. Uh,
there probably
>> Let's just improvise and see where it
goes. Um, so yeah, guy, it's a special
it's a special occasion. What's this
special occasion?
>> Yeah, it is. It's a it's a big day for
us. We are unveiling Tessle. We're
launching Tesla's products, which we'll
talk a fair bit about. Uh, and it's it's
exciting. We've been building this for
quite a while. Uh, so we can't wait to
tell you more about it.
>> Yeah. And so it's available right now on
Tesl.io. So go ahead, have a play, see
what we got. But guy, why don't you tell
us what are we launching?
>> Sure. So we're launching uh two products
actually. sort of can't uh you know
named it twice. Yeah, it's like why one
you know why choose. Um so actually uh
in general they're both in the world of
specdriven development. We'll talk more
about that. Uh but the first one is the
Tesla framework which is uh a solution
that integrates into your agent and
helps it uh start developing in the sort
of specdriven approach as we'll explain.
And the second is the Tesla spec
registry uh which helps agents use open
source better and expands into generally
distributing information through specs
to agents about everything that's not in
their codebase. So both products
together are to us a part of what is
specdriven development. Uh and yeah,
we'll sort of explain about both. But as
Simon pointed out, we're going to
blabber here a little bit and explain
more about it, but if you're keen to try
them out, just check out des.io and
start playing with the tools.
>> Yeah. Yeah. 2 minutes into this episode,
you might as well stop now and just go
and try it out.
>> Consider your life choices.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. So, so let let's
talk about every every good solution guy
has a has a pain. Well, some some I
always used to laugh at when people said
blockchain. Oh, yeah. That's a that's a
solution looking for a problem, right?
Tell me what the problem is that that
that you know we're trying to solve here
at Tesla, but also AI and D and things
like that is trying to solve.
>> Sure. So we have the the meta problem
that is semi-pro semi- opportunity uh
that I think you've heard us talk about
a fair bit which is that uh software
today is code ccentric and that in that
code we forget what we wanted the
product built for in the first place and
uh and that we think there's an
opportunity to change to this spec
driven development world in which your
software is defined through its specs.
Um but that's that's the vision that's
the destination. But the more concrete
problem we're talking about now and
we're trying to tackle is around agentic
development. Uh and if you're using
agents to develop then you've probably
seen that agents are powerful but
they're also unreliable. Uh and they're
definitely overconfident, right? So you
would uh you would ask them for
something that go off and they rush to
start coding the first solution that
comes to mind. Uh, and oftentimes that
would be the wrong thing or they
misunderstood you and you find yourself
needing to fix it after the fact or they
would make things up, right? They would
say they're done when they're not really
like they they say, "Hey, I fixed the
problem." Or like, "Oh, 59 out of 75
tests pass. I think I'm good." It's
like, "No, you're not." Um, and sort of
similarly, they hallucinate information
that is outside. They hallucinate APIs.
They hallucinate uh all libraries
sometimes. And all of those really
culminates as you try to build bigger
and bigger. And so you you use the
agents, you wrangle them, you review
them, and you get them to a to a safe
spot, and then you add a feature, and
they break something else.
>> And so all of those are are sort of this
reliability problems that mean that if
you're using agents, uh you are in this
perpetual review motion. You are just
trying to understand what have they
done, was it correct, review the
products and the outputs. And when you
encounter a problem or something that
was incorrect, uh it it's really hard to
fix things uh in hindsight cuz you you
kind of need to go back. How far back do
I go? Do I revert the changes
altogether? Uh and I think this is the
biggest pain that uh people using agents
today experience. For those who stick to
it and build with agents, it's, you
know, they have to build their
techniques and and it's the challenge
that they face dayto-day is how do I
minimize the amount of reviewing that I
need to do and get these agents just to
do what I what I need them to do. And
for many people, it's actually a
blocker. They can't get into agentic
development because the systems are just
too reliable. All these agents are just
too unreliable uh to uh sorry let me
sort of save for some people uh they
just can't get into agentic development
today at all uh because of this blocker
the the systems and these agents are
just too unreliable to use them in a
professional setting and so we think we
can address many of these problems
through specs and spec driven
development and that's what both of our
products are trying to solve. Super
interesting. I I mean for me personally
I I guess two of the pains which which
really spring to mind for me is I I
start coding with agents and you feel
that magic. You feel that kind of like
the true vibe coding nature of I give it
a little I get a lot back. But then as
soon as the app gets to almost like this
certain size where it has an amount of
functionality and capability, there's
almost like you hit this ceiling whereby
exactly what you kind of like referred
to where I change one bit and a whole
bunch of other things change even if
I've actually already specified this is
how I want that to work. It almost
neglects some of my previous comments
even though that is part of the context
from the from the original conversation
um and so forth. it it makes it almost
like you can't continue with the agent
because it's it's it becomes more work
to kind of keep it on on track and that
becomes that becomes a huge huge pain.
the the other the other problem that I
have is sometimes you get to this stage
where you actually have to almost give
up and you have to say almost like I
have to start again it it's got itself
in such a knot I can't continue down
this path and it's the these are the
limitations of the of the vibe coding
way which actually uh almost like a
blocker from going into that kind of
more into that actual enterprise-like
production style level of of reliable
code. So, so yeah, I think these are
like super important and common pain
points that that both we and most of the
world who have been using AI have
suffered and and and feel day-to-day
basis. What are the two products then
that uh that that we're releasing?
>> Uh so two products both very exciting.
Um the first one is the Tesla framework
and that is really a specri development
framework that connects to your agent
via MCP. So we support all the agents
that support it. Uh and guides it to uh
capture its intent in specs before it
builds, right? So you come along and you
give it an instruction, whatever, build
me a uh to-do app or whatever it is. Uh
and before it jumps into code, it first
creates a spec thanks to using Tesla's
tools and thanks to Tesla's guidance to
say what is it that it wants to build in
a quick and easy to understand format
and then it goes off to build it. And
have you had a case where you ran along
or you gave an instruction and the agent
rushed and they ended up building the
wrong thing?
>> It's it's not just daily, maybe hourly
when I when I when I use agents. Um, and
it's it's I guess a twofold thing. One
where I either give it an instruction
and it hasn't quite understood exactly
what I meant. And it's because I love to
short prompt because I get, you know,
value and speed out of short prompting.
Uh the other of course is where I you
know I ask it for a small a small change
in a larger app and it actually then
goes ahead and starts changing other
pieces expands it of the
>> oh gosh it's frustrating. So, so that's
the sort of the first goal is separate
intent from implementation and capture
what it means to build in a spec and
then once you are comfortable with you
know the the intent and with what has
been built and you're happy with it uh
then Tesla offers you an easy way to now
generate tests uh with sort of a single
command uh and this is done because the
spec is actually designed up front to be
built with a lot of test cases in mind
that serve as examples when you
initially generate Right? But then those
uh are are sort of the key definitions
to go off and create tests and the agent
needs to work a little bit harder to be
able to generate those tests. Needs to
set up a test environment sometimes
iterate uh but it does it quite
autonomously and once it works those
serve as regression tests and so now you
know that it would not do as you
mentioned before you know you you make a
change then goes off and it breaks
something else.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And and that kind of like
leads into whether you prefer to do a
test-driven tests up front kind of phase
or whether you want to do that
innovation and creation first and then
once you're happy with what you have do
tests later. And I think there's never a
right or a wrong answer. It massively
depends on either organization or
individual preference of how they want
to build. But you have both solutions uh
with that same uh centricity over the
specification.
>> Yeah. Exactly. And there's no we we we
we went a lot of back and forth on like
do we do we want to be opinionated about
one versus the other. But in practice
even the same person in the same company
for certain tasks. Sometimes you want to
create the spec, review the spec, ensure
that uh what you mean to build that your
intent is well captured that the test
cases represent what you want etc. And
you're willing to invest that time
because you have enough opinions and
it's important enough or maybe unique
enough. it's rules of some new game or
whatever it may be. And so then you want
to invest that time and and the Tesla
framework supports that and it's very
easy and natural to do it. And then once
you have defined those you sort of send
the agent off to build and you have
those guardrails so the agent can work
more autonomously until it gets it
right. But the other mode uh that we've
started calling vibesing is also legit,
right? As we've heard Ollie from uh Data
Dog, the CEO and founder of Data Dog
tell us in a previous episode, you know,
the the biggest lie that customers tell
you is that if it's important, they'll
invest the time. And in practice, what
we see on ourselves and on our users is
that often times people just want to get
to working code as quickly as possible.
And so uh this vibespecking mode is one
in which you indeed you you don't create
the test up front. You don't really know
what it is that you want. So you just
flow with it. You allow the agent to
make the decisions as you did before.
You're just now capturing those
decisions in these different documents.
So it's easy for you to proceed. And
even if you've done that, those
regression tests still serve as a
guardrail for future evolutions of it.
So even if you went the casual mode, you
still get some extra protection.
>> Yeah. And ultimately you get the same
thing at the end of the day. You have
your code, you have those tests that
that make sure that the code that's
generated satisfies the specification
and the specification really importantly
still holds all the intents. Uh whether
you go tests first, whether you go tests
after, it's it's not opinionated in in
in such a way.
>> Exactly. you actually you you can now
continue and you have something you
actually didn't have before in software
development as a whole which is you now
have this long-term memory as the specs
get committed to your codebase of what
your product should do uh which we
actually don't really have in software
development today. We have you know docs
or or such but because they are not the
source they're not the the the file
through which changes get applied then
they often times fall out of date as we
all know.
>> Not that not that dusty PRD down in the
basement you're talking about. Exactly.
It's not these sort of fragmented
requirements nor even sort of user docs.
And so you have you have these specs and
the specs capture your intent over time.
Uh and you can keep coming back to them.
And it's an easy way to manage tests and
relate them to the product. And so the
the true maybe biggest value of the
Tesla framework actually comes as you
continue building and continue evolving
because you have these specs as part of
your codebase and defining what your
product should do. What the framework
also does is it helps you ensure again
with minimal effort that they are always
up to speed. Whenever we can, we end up
modifying files through the spec. When
you call an edit, you call the Tessle
edit tool and that modifies the spec
first and then modifies the code. And
when the agent uh misbehaves or when you
had some good reason to change a code
file or a test file, we have means of
detecting that and going back and
updating the spec. And so we really try
to make it as seamless as possible to
always keep the specs up to date and to
ensure that changes get applied through
the specs really allowing you to sort of
scale and grow. And we think that the
the more information gets captured in
the specs over time, the more you can
tap into the creative power, if you
will, of the LLM or the ability to try
many many different things and try to
make code that is faster, that is, you
know, adaptable to change something
from, you know, a Python environment to
a TypeScript to a Java uh and uh and not
need to worry that your functionality
breaks in the process. So, a lot of
value upfront as you create. Uh but
really probably the biggest treasure
trove is uh as you as you grow.
>> Yeah. And these specs really build up to
the life cycle of the of the
application, right? They just stay with
the with the test with the code all the
way through and continually you as a
user are focusing more on the
specification than than anything else.
>> And that's a very important
clarification because I think in the
industry today we use specs for various
purposes. I think uh in the sort of
naent agentic dev world and for many
people specs are uh about a transition
from point A to point B from state A to
state B uh we that's not how we think of
specs we do create plans as a natural
part of the uh of the Tesla usage and
those plans are indeed their life cycle
or lifespan is the the the lifespan of
the change but the specs are really
about the definitive document that
describes functionality and their
lifespan is the lif of your codebase.
>> Yeah. Amazing. So, product one, the
Tesla framework, the ability to to to
create uh using a a a specd driven
approach, spec driven development
approach. Um you mentioned about agents
being being a little bit uh a little bit
dodgy, a little bit a little bit wary.
Tell us a little bit about product two
and how that kind of like helps keeps
keep these agents in the rails.
>> Uh sure. So the second product which I'm
very excited about is the Tesla spec
registry. Going back a little bit to the
pain point, I think what you see with
agents is uh sometimes they don't know
something and they don't know they don't
know uh or
the story of my life. I'm basically an
agent.
>> They're kind of uh they're kind of
overconfident. You know, I'm not I'm
going to let that slide.
>> I feel seen now.
>> So the most evident version of that is
when they use an API, a third party API
or or an open source library API. uh if
you're using something that is like
straight up in the mainstream then they
know they're amazing at it. If you're
using something that's a little bit off
or using a slightly older version of a
popular library or even more if you're
using a new version that didn't exist
yet when those models were trained uh
typically what the agents would do is
they would just make it up as they go
and they would use you know false APIs
or flawed one and sometimes they would
just really get stuck in that mode and
they would just sort of waste time and
money trying to get there and never get
out of it and sometimes they would
eventually figure it out but it was you
know timeconuming costly And they often
times are left with a slightly messy
implementation. And have you experienced
things like that?
>> So much. So much. And it's particularly
because you know AI is great at when it
looks at its when it you know trains on
on a huge amount of of open source
libraries with tons of different
versions on there. when things and I'm
talking about the Java world here, but
when things progress over years and
years and years and years, there are so
many API changes from different
libraries whereby the most popular is
really the one it's going to be trained
on. And I'm not always using the most
popular because I sometimes run on an
old stack or I'm sometimes bleeding edge
with some of the things I'm using. And
it's not just as much a hallucination as
it is a I'm assuming this is the version
you're running on without actually using
the correct context to build against uh
when and generating my app. huge
problem.
>> Precisely. And so we This is really a
kind of a context problem, right? They
don't have the right information at the
right time. Sometimes because they
literally do not have the info like a
brand new library version. Sometimes
because sort of a a less statistically
significant bit of information. Uh and
sometimes it's indeed information
there's no way for them to have like
your team's specific best practices or
context. Um and so what we believe and
enable with the spec registry is to make
that knowledge a part of your project.
Um so we introduce a new dependency
system that the spec registry enables
that is a dependency system for
knowledge for specs. Uh you would have a
a new manifest file in your project that
references certain spec packs packages
of specs with the right information to
be able to work on this codebase. More
specifically for open source, we have
pre-populated uh the registry with over
10,000 usage specs which are uh pre like
we generated them by analyzing the code
of specific versions of libraries uh and
additional information about those
libraries of you know usage online that
is all version aware and we package them
up in these easy to consume kind of
nuggets of knowledge for the agent. So
these are markdown files with the right
sections. they are split up into
multiple files so the agent can load the
right thing at the right time and so
let's say you're using some library at
you know version old then the agent will
uh you you will add that you would use
Tesla registry search to find uh the
usage spec you will it will be added to
your manifest file and those usage specs
will be downloaded to your uh your
project just like node modules or other
dependencies uh and then using tesla
tools and even natively the agent can
then find them and use the information
correctly and you know that this
information is there. It is uh uh
correct for your specific project. It is
uh um kind of always available to all
the agents. You're not dependent on them
realizing they need to go seek it out or
misunderstanding it. Uh and as your
software stack changes or as your
practices change, so does the
information that you make available to
the agents. And and it's important to
hear to raise that distinction between
the spec that you kind of like referred
to earlier where we're creating a
specification using the Tesla framework
and that specification allows agents to
create code. It's effectively a
blueprint of this is how I want you to
build my application. The usage spec
that you're referring to is quite
different. It's telling the agent how I
should use these various libraries or
components so I can code against them.
It kind of reminds me, I don't know how
well this will travel to our listeners,
but uh the Hannes manual for cars. It's
like the the book that that kind of like
tells you every little bit about how a
component works in a car. It's great to
understand how every single component
could work and can work, but it doesn't
necessarily tell you how to drive the
car. I wouldn't look at that in order
for me to, you know, be able to to use a
car correctly. That's the usage that I
need. And so if you go in just
understanding how a library can do
things, what APIs are available and so
forth, that only gives me half a story.
It doesn't actually tell me how I should
use it, examples, best practices. That's
a key distinction which usage specs here
give us.
>> Uh correct. And I think we talk a lot
about what is uh what what should be in
the spec. And specs can hold many
things. and we find ourselves now
defining a type a functional spec versus
a usage spec eventually when we think
about spec driven development and spec
driven specentric software. Um then we
oftenimes all of these will be part of
the software package itself because um
you know when you are creating a library
you the information that you need to be
able to uh uh regenerate that library
again again for instance that might be
more of a functional spec might be a bit
more technical but uh understanding that
library both for the consumer and for
future developers actually starts
looking a lot more like a user spec. Uh
so at the moment we are you know not
there isn't much software out there that
is uh that is defined by specs and so we
are creating these kind of docs for
agents you know for software that has
been built in a code-centric fashion and
we make it accessible in a very kind of
agent uh friendly way right with a good
ax um so that they can consume it and
make it a part of that project you know
a dependency system for knowledge uh and
again we we've kind of spent some
inference dollars so you don't have to
uh to make this information available to
you so you can install it now and just
make it you know make your agents use
open source better. Uh but we think
conceptually
uh there's there's more information that
needs to be made available to agents
than just usage specs. They could be
around how do I add analytics to a
project in my specific organization,
right? How do we run a security scan
over here and fix the vulnerabilities?
Which logger should I use? Like all of
those might be things that the agent can
intuitit or make up, but what it would
make up is going to be inconsistent and
often times incorrect. So you need to
get the right information to it and
you're right and you want this
information to always be available for
this project and you want it to be cross
agent as your team changes and moves uh
agents over time. So right now use it to
make your agents use open source better
and over time start thinking about what
would you publish into this registry and
what else would you like to find there
to consume. So the Tesla framework, the
Tesla's spec registry guy, shut up and
take my money. I can use all of this
today right now, right? If I go to
Tesla.io.
>> Uh so almost almost.
So the Tesla spec registry is now
available in open beta. So you can go to
tesl.io and with a couple of clicks, you
can get it installed and integrated on
your uh on your agent environment and
start using it right away. uh and would
love for you to try that and to send us
feedback uh to build it up. The Tesla
framework uh is still released in a
controlled beta. So you can find Yeah.
>> Why why
so the development framework has a lot
of moving parts and there are many many
many ways that you can use it. Uh and uh
today there's just a lot of freedom and
we feel like there are too many
opportunities for users to shoot
themselves in the foot and so we are
making it available in a controlled
beta. It's still like a large scale
controlled beta and we want to just
evolve the on boarding experience, the
right guard rails, the right learnings
so that not everybody sort of shaves on
the same practice. We think in general
creating the right spec driven
development methodology is not something
we've just solved. We are launching a
version of that and we want to iterate
on it with the world with the community
and so we'd love for you to register and
request access. Uh, and we we intend to
give many people access as we learn, but
we're just going to throttle that or
sort of stagger that a little bit so
that not everybody encounters the same
problems. And as we improve, we hope
fairly quickly to get to something that
is an open beta and then eventually
we'll take your money.
>> Awesome.
So, uh, right now if you go to Tesla,
you can have access to the to the, uh,
to the spec registry. Tesla spec
registry open. um the the Tesla
framework uh is being opened up to many
more people on a throttled uh beta and
you can sign up uh to the waiting list
correct for that. One of the interesting
things which kind of like me and the
team are doing here at Tesla as well is
we're opening up we're not we know we're
not trying to keep everything hidden.
We're opening up much much more of of
our docs so you can see how you can use
the Tesla framework even if you don't
have access today. There's a bunch of
videos on Teslio to be able to see uh
Tesla, the Tesla framework in action and
so you can see exactly what what we're
talking about here. And in fact going
forward uh why don't I bring Macy on
again? Do you remember Macy Baker for
those who who watching a few episodes
>> definitely want her on the show much
more than me.
>> Let's get let's get some demos going and
we'll show we'll show you the framework
in action as well. This is a part of
what makes today special for us is this
big unveiling. There's been there are
many thoughts you know like a long
process to get to to the situation. So
we're happy to build in public uh even
as we slightly slightly control access
to uh to to just sort of help it all go
smoothly.
>> Yeah. And the best way to build in
public of course is to is to get user
and community feedback. Uh the best way
to do that join us on Discord. Links
will be links will be in the in the show
notes. Uh our Discord server. Um there's
there's Tesla channels couple of Tesla
channels now in the in the AI native uh
dev community. So join that tell us what
you're using there and you'll be uh
joined uh to the correct roles and the
correct channels where you can discuss
both about the spec registry as well as
uh the Tesla framework.
>> Yeah. And indeed we're we're seeking a
lot of feedback and there's a chance
that if you're uh a valuable feedback
provider even if it's critical feedback
on it maybe you you also get bumped up
the weight list for the uh
>> popularity contest. I see. I see.
>> It's a usefulness.
>> It's a a usefulness contest. Excellent.
Um, so yeah, you talked about, you know,
the the story a little bit about what
we've what we've been through. Tesla's
obviously, you know, not not a a fresh
uh company. It's it's been around for
over a year now. I remember the the the
episode that we did with 125 mil of
funding and things like that. It's an
it's a it's an established company. Tell
us a little bit about the journey uh
that that Tesla has been through to to
get to this point to where we are today.
So first of all I think the company is
over almost a year and a half old uh and
uh consistently we have believed that
specentric software is the future uh and
and many of the core concepts of how we
imagined spec centric software or sort
of specdriven development uh to to look
like are actually the same surprisingly
the same uh but we also knew that we're
anchored in the future and that the LLMs
can't quite do it uh today. And so we
went through sort of I'd say maybe a
couple of chapters over almost a year.
Uh at first it's kind of the navy uh
phase. And so we you know we could
imagine it and so we said fine let's
build a specri development uh platform
that allows you to create in the sort of
uh uh webish environment software
through specs. H and we really were very
uh very bullish in what can we do in a
period of time. uh and that took maybe 6
months to get a better appreciation of
the uh level of capability of LLMs at
the time and uh and understand that
there's still a bit of a journey to be
able to deliver. we were to deliver that
and so we were left with with a lot of
ideas about what's the correct
destination uh but it was just a bit too
much and then we switched to a more kind
of controlled environment in which you
could create software components
uh through a very controlled web-based
development path uh and we indeed
managed to build something that matches
the capabilities of the LLM so you could
create software libraries with Tessle in
a spec driven fashion in a next next
experience and users were were quite
interested in that but it was it was too
narrow and too big a change
>> opinionated as well. I remember when we
were building that it took us through a
number of stages as well where you need
to be in this stage first then you go to
the code gen then you go to the test
then you export and publish blah blah
blah and and you know we went through a
number of changes even there just
working out if it's linear do users want
to jump through stages it it's a complex
thing
>> part of the reason that we went through
that is because the elements were just
not good enough and so uh we we needed
to kind of hold their hand and be very
specific but eventually the product we
ended ended up with was was not worth
the the leap. You know, it was too
narrow to and too different. And so, you
couldn't really develop software in this
fashion. And so in the last chapter,
which is, you know, the one that I feel
like we've we've uh hit the mark, first
of all, we said, hey, we can't we need
to abandon the sort of closed web- based
controlled environment and embrace the
the roots of local uh file-based, you
know, very open and tinkerable uh
development environment and the CLI. And
then uh agents came along and I think
agents were key for in two ways. Uh you
know, in part is because of the
capability. So they they unlock an
ability for AI to generate a lot more
and we have been building basically a a
version of an agent in the previous
iterations of it. Uh but there was
clearly a lot more and especially with
cloud code and the terminal based
approach there was a lot more that they
can do. But more importantly it it uh
surfaced uh an immediate version of the
pain that we're addressing. Uh and so we
from the beginning said the pain we're
addressing is is this sort of big pain
of software development. You develop
software and over time you forget why
what the software is meant to do and
you're just left with the code uh and
then over years that problem uh
manifests and software becomes fragile
because you forget what it was. agents
is like a microcosmos of that, right?
You they're they've got amnesia, right?
You sort of you tell them uh you tell
them to do something today and the next
day they forget it. They don't remember
it anymore. Uh you nobody has knowledge
of the code, you know, because they've
written it and so nobody understands the
code or any meaning to uh that is within
it. And you're you're really face first
uh with the problem that the code just
doesn't have enough information. Um and
then they they have all these other
symptoms that are like in software
development. Sometimes they
misunderstand you just like developers
might uh but they just it's a faster
iteration and therefore they build the
wrong thing you know and that fixing
problems after the fact is harder. And a
great developer today you come and you
tell them hey I need this change in the
system they will stop and say okay
what's what's the product impact what
are the use cases that you're trying to
satisfy so I can prioritize my work
accordingly. Uh and so to an extent
that's what we're doing to the agents.
we're trying to make them do that. So I
I think it is very kind of invigorating
and it's like it just feels a lot better
to say okay we we are we remain true to
this vision of spectriven development
and again a lot of the concepts are the
same ones that we've been iterating on
for a year and a half now but we now
have a real user with a real pain that
is incremental that we can build with
that we can make that user successful at
using agents better. Uh and so I think
this is the chapter that we're in and I
I've sort of been saying like we knew
the destination but uh now we found the
trail head you know we we were sort of
wondering this path and saying okay fine
but where does the path start and now we
find the trail head uh and now we run
>> I think it's amazing how this is the
first time I personally have joined you
or anyone on a journey so early in in in
a startup stage and I think one thing
that I I think is is is quite quite
amazing is how startups can so quickly
pivot and say, "Look, this isn't the
way. This is the way. This isn't the
way. This is the way." And and recognize
that based on the on the changes that
have happened in the industry, and of
course, AI, nothing's been nothing's
changed the industry so much as as AI in
in in as many months. But um but yeah,
it it's it's that bravery and courage to
be able to say actually look, this is
the change here. We're not going to
continue on this path. The way in which
we tackle them. the way in which our
users are using technology today changes
our approach and the change the the the
the path changes quite significantly. It
does. And that's actually also probably
the the the bit that I think is most
critical and that I'm most proud of the
team for doing is really this
adaptability, right? Like we have we
have a great team here. It's not a small
team now. We're sort of uh uh 37 people
I think now.
>> And you know it's a lot of people
they've they've written a lot of code
which they've subsequently deleted. Uh
sometimes because we've shifted and
we're in this chapter. sometimes because
uh new evolutions with LLMs have kind of
rendered it unnecessary. Um and and
those are that that's not easy. You
know, it's easy to get attached to the
thing that you're building. It's easy to
uh to sort of stick to to a path. What
do you mean? You know, like I I've built
this and I'm I'm kind of passionate
about this creation that I have. Uh and
I think our team is very focused on, you
know, we understand this vision. We want
to bring it to life and we're trying to
provide value to users. In fact,
probably the biggest complaint, you
know, amidst the teams is like we want
more users because everybody's so
attuned to say, okay, like I want to I
want to show this to more and more
users. Now, of course, we've had users
all along, uh, but not in vast
quantities as we're sort of exploring
the way. Uh and so everybody is very
keen to doing it but super proud of the
team for for for being willing to sort
of you know throw away you know past
work if it is not the right path forward
for being kind of uh no ego uh and
aligning with the group because we're
again we're sort of a larger group now
uh and coming along as we as we make
changes in the sort of nebulous
potential paths uh and I guess most
immediately and rallying towards uh this
launch like a lot of work got done uh
over the last few weeks and I I think
now we we get the best opportunity of
letting the team shine which is engaging
with users, responding to uh to problems
and continuing to build with sort of the
speed that we have here.
>> Yeah, it's amazing and of course that
whole team is ready to now engage and
chat much more publicly than ever before
on on on the Discord. So
>> this pretty much wraps it up. extremely
exciting news and amazing uh to be able
to share this with with the broader
audience. And Guy, you'll be on Discord
just as everyone will.
>> I'll I'll be on Discord. I'm probably
not the sort of the smartest person for
you to sort of engage with to sort of
solve problems there, but if you want
some sort of philosophical ramble, I'll
be there. I'll be there. Uh yeah, and we
do look forward to having all of you
join us on the Discord and engage in
this in this journey. Again, we're not
claiming to have solved spec driven
development. Uh we understand these
things take iteration. Uh, and we're
here to iterate and fix problems that
you encounter, hear needs that you have
that we've not yet solved. And so very
very keen for you to to try it out, you
know, both the uh the spec registry and
the framework and to tell us what you
think and just stay engaged in the
community as we make more and more kind
of concepts of this journey available.
>> Absolutely. So tesla.io uh you can use
the spec registry right now. Tell us
what you think on Discord and of course
sign up for the Tesla framework. um uh
throttle beater uh program as well. We'd
love to get your feedback on that. Once
again, guy, really appreciate this chat.
It's great to It's great to be here in
person again.
>> Indeed. Indeed. Exciting time. Thank
you, Simon. And uh yeah, now the fun
part begins.
>> Thanks for listening and tune in to the
next episode.